this is a librivox recording all librivox recordings are in the public
domain for more information or to volunteer please visit librivox.org this
reading by J Hall the Wonderful Wizard of Oz by l frank Baum Chapter 3
How Dorothy Saved the Scarecrow When Dorothy was left alone she began to feel
hungry. So she went to the cupboard and cut herself some bread, which she spread
with butter. She gave some to Toto, and taking a pail from the shelf she carried
it down to the little brook and filled it with clear, sparkling water. Toto ran
over to the trees and began to bark at the birds sitting there. Dorothy went to
get him, and saw such delicious fruit hanging from the branches that she
gathered some of it, finding it just what she wanted to help out her breakfast.
Then she went back to the house, and having helped herself and Toto to a good
drink of cool, clear water, she set about making ready for the journey to the City
of Emeralds. Dorothy had only one other dress, but that happened to be clean and
it was hanging on a peg beside her bed.
It was gingham, with checks of white and blue; and although the blue was somewhat
faded with many washings, it was still a pretty frock. The girl washed herself
carefully, dressed herself in the clean Bigham and tied her pink Sun bonnet on
her head. She took a little basket and filled it with bread from the cupboard,
laying a white cloth over the top. Then she looked down at her feet and noticed
how old and worn her shoes were due for a long journey, Toto,”
she said aunt Ono looked up into her face with his little black eyes and
wagged his tail to show he knew what she meant.
At that moment Dorothy saw lying on the table the silver shoes that had belonged
to the Witch of the East. “I wonder if they'll fit me,” she said to Toto.
“They would be just the thing to take a long walk in or they could not wear out.”
She took off her old leather shoes and tried on the silver ones, which fit her
as well as if they had been made for Finally she picked up her basket. “Come along, Toto,”
she said. “We will go to the Emerald City
and ask the Great Oz how to get back to Kansas again.” She closed the door, locked
it, and put the key carefully in the pocket of her dress. And so, with Toto
trotting along soberly behind her, she started on her journey.
There were several roads nearby, but it did not take her long to find the one
paved with yellow bricks. Within a short time she was walking briskly towards the Emerald City,
her silver shoes tinkling merrily on the hard, yellow road bed The sun shone
bright and the birds sang sweetly, and Dorothy did not feel nearly so bad as
you might think a little girl who had been suddenly whisk away from her own
country and sat down in the midst of a strange land. She was surprised, as she
walked along, to see how pretty the country was about her. There were neat
fences at the sides of the road, painted a dainty blue color, and beyond them were
fields of grain and vegetables and abundance. Evidently the Munchkins were
good farmers and able to raise large crops. Once in a while she would pass a
house, and the people came out to look at her and bow low as she went by; for
everyone knew she had been the means of destroying the Wicked Witch and setting
them free from bondage. The houses of the Munchkins were odd-looking dwellings, for
each was round, with a big dome for a roof. All were painted blue, for in this
country of the East blue was the favorite color. Toward evening, when
Dorothy was tired with her long walk and began to wonder where she should pass
the night, she came to a house rather larger than the rest. On the green long
before at many men and women were dancing.
Five little Fiddler's played as loudly as possible, and the people were laughing
and singing, while a big table nearby was loaded with delicious fruits and nuts,
pies and cakes, and many other good things to eat people greeted Dorothy
kindly, and invited her to supper and to pass the night with them; for this was
the home of one of the richest Munchkins in the land, and his friends were
gathered with him to celebrate their freedom from the bondage of the Wicked
Witch. Dorothy ate a hearty supper and was waited upon by the rich Munchkin himself,
whose name was Bach Then she sat upon a SETI and watched the people dance. When
Bach saw her silver shoes he said, “You must be a great sorceress.” “Why ask the
girl. “Because you wear silver shoes and have killed the Wicked Witch. Besides, you
have white in your frock, and only witches and sorceress is wear white.” “My
dress is blue and white checked,” said Dorothy, smoothing out the wrinkles in it.
“It is kind of you to wear that,” said Bock Blue is the color of the Munchkins, and
white is the witch color. So we know you are a friendly witch.” Dorothy did not
know what to say to this, for all the people seem to think her a witch, and she
knew very well she was only an ordinary little girl who had come by the chance
of a cyclone into a strange land. When she had tired watching the dancing Bach
led her into the house, where he gave her a room with a pretty
bed in it. The sheets were made of blue cloth, and Dorothy slept soundly in them
till morning, with Toto curled up on the blue rug beside her. She ate a hearty
breakfast, and watched a wee Munchkin baby, who played with Toto and pulled his
tail and crowed and laughed in a way that greatly amused Dorothy. Toto was a
fine curiosity to all the people, for they had never seen a dog before. “How far
is it to the Emerald City?” the girl asked.
“I do not know,” answered Bock gravely, “for I have never been there. It is better for
people to keep away from Oz, unless they have business with him. But is a long way
to the Emerald City, and it will take you many days. The country here is rich and
pleasant, but you must pass through rough and dangerous places before you reach
the end of your journey.” This worried Dorothy a little, but she knew that only
the Great Oz could help her get back to Kansas again, so she bravely resolved not
to turn back. She bade her friends goodbye and again started along the road
of yellow brick. When she had gone several miles she thought she would stop
to rest, and so she climbed to the top of the fence beside the road and sat down.
There was a great corn field beyond the fence, and not far away she saw a
crow placed high on a pole to keep the birds from the ripe corn.
Dorothy leaned her chin upon her hand and gazed thoughtfully at the Scarecrow.
Its head was a small sack stuffed with straw, with eyes, nose, and mouth painted
on it to represent a face. An old, pointed blue hat, that had belonged to some
Munchkin, was perched on his head, and the rest of the figure was a blue suit of
clothes, worn and faded, which had also been stuffed with straw. On the feet were
some old boots with blue tops, such as every man wore in this country, and the
figure was raised above the stalks of corn by means of the poles stuck up its
back. While Dorothy was looking earnestly into the queer, painted face of the
Scarecrow, she was surprised to see one of the eyes slowly wink at her. She
thought she must have been mistaken at first, for none of the scarecrows in
Kansas ever winked but presently the figure nodded its head to her in a
friendly way. Then she climbed down from the fence and walked up to it, while Toto
ran around the pole embarked Good day,” said the Scarecrow, in a rather husky
voice. “Did you speak?” asked the girl, in wonder. “Certainly,” answered the Scarecrow.
“How do you do?” “I’m pretty well, thank you,” replied Dorothy politely. “How do you do?”
“I’m not feeling well,” said the Scarecrow, with a smile, “for it is very tedious
being perched up here night and day to scare away crows.” “Can’t you get down?”
asked Dorothy. “No, for this pole is stuck up my back. If you will please take away
the pole I shall be greatly obliged to you.” Dorothy reached up both arms and
lifted the figure off the pole, for, being stuffed with straw, it was quite light.
“Thank you very much,” said the Scarecrow, when he had been set
down on the ground. “I feel like a new man.” Dorothy was puzzled at this, for it
sounded queer to hear a stuffed man speak, and to see him bow and walk along
beside her. “Who are you?” asked the Scarecrow when he had stretched himself
and yond And where are you going?” “My name is door
he said the girl, “and I am going to the
Emerald City, to ask the Great Oz to send me back to Kansas.” “Where is the Emerald
City?” he inquired. “And who is Oz?” “Why, don’t you know?” she returned, in surprise. “No,
indeed. I don’t know anything. You see, I am stuffed, so I have no brains at all,”
he answered sadly. “Oh,” said Dorothy, “I’m awfully sorry for you.” “Do you think,” he
asked, “if I go to the Emerald City with you, that Oscar give me some brains?”
“I cannot tell,” she returned, “but you may come with me, if you like. If
the Oz will not give you any brains you will be no worse off than you are now.”
“That is true,” said the Scarecrow. “You see,” he continued competently I don’t mind my
legs and arms and body being stuffed, because I cannot get hurt. If anyone
treads on my toes or sticks a pin into
me, it doesn’t matter, for I can’t feel it.
But I do not want people to call me a fool, and if my head stay stuffed with
straw instead of with brains, as yours is, how am I ever to know anything?” “I
understand how you feel,” said the little girl, who was truly sorry for him. “If you
will come with me I’ll ask Oz to do all he can for you.” “Thank you,”
he answered gratefully. They walked back to the road. Dorothy helped him over the
fence, and they started along the path of yellow brick for the Emerald City. Toto
did not like this addition to the party at first. He smelled around the stuffed
man as if he suspected there might be a nest of rats in the straw, and he often
growled in an unfriendly way at the Scarecrow. “Don’t mind Toto,” said Dorothy
to her new friend. “He never bites.” “Oh, I’m not afraid,” replied the Scarecrow. “He
can’t hurt the straw. Do let me carry that basket for you. I shall not mind it,
for I can’t get tired. I’ll tell you a secret,” he continued, as he walked along.
“There was only one thing in the world I am afraid of.” “What is that?” asked Dorothy;
“the munchkins farmer who made you know the Scarecrow; “it’s a lighted match end of chapter 3